CARLOS EDUARDO CARMO DO NASCIMENTO

Dublin – Ireland | +353 83 321 9946 | carloseduardocarmo19@gmail.com
https://www.linkedin.com/in/karlos-developer | GitHub: https://github.com/Eduardo2804 |

Eligible to work in Ireland

Recent graduated in Computing Science at CCT College and Bilingual (English and Portuguese), many years working for Brazilian Institute of Geography and Statistics with data collecting and analysis also with a valuable academic experience in web and mobile development — backend and frontend using SOLID principles with Object-Oriented Java programming. Capable of quickly learning new technologies and problem resolutions.

Technical Skills:

• Web Development: Back end: Java, JavaScript / Front end: HTML5, CSS3, JS, Bootstrap5

• Database: SQL, MySQL, SQLite

• Web frames: Angular, React-Native, Node modules

• Mobile development: Ionic 6

Operating systems: Linux and Windows

• Version control: GIT, GITPOD

EDUCATION

Bachelor/Diploma in Computer Science, CTT College – Ireland 2021 – 2022

GPA: second class Honours 2:2

Petroleum and Gas Technology of Production 2010 - 2012

GPA: First Class Honours 1:1

Further Education: Assembly and maintenance of computers with Hardware and Networks, Microlins College

(2006)

ACADEMIC EXPERIENCE

Bachelor/Diploma in Science Computing Student, CTT College – Ireland

2021 - 2022

- Studied cloud-based web and mobile development, data management, networking and virtualization, operating systems and architecture, and mobile development projects
- Guided technology Project: For the final project, created an SPA with a booking system for repairs, using the SPRING BOOT as framework in the back end and it was easily to connect with front end and database creating all tables with every attributes also with a register page to register staffs and offered services.
- Web development & Data Manipulation: Designed and implemented a database for the HR department, translated a database model into a live database using SQL commands, then built the back end using JAVA7
- Networking and virtualisation: Built a small network to connect the users through virtual servers, cloning VM's and CLI, setting administrator passwords and firewalls using best practices

- Operating systems and Architecture: Developed the OS&A and N&V project, built a small network for the end users using Ubuntu OS, then recommended solutions based on best practices in the maintenance of a secure system, identifying risks and implementing recovery measures
- Software developments fundamentals: Created a programme for a Rugby Club's management, illustrated and related object-oriented concepts (encapsulation, inheritance, polymorphism)
- Algorithms and constructors: Created custom data structures and algorithms for a library system to manage stock and borrowings, while using various data structures available, such as lists, queues and stacks
- Mobile development: Developed an API-based mobile application project in Ionic using Angular, based on the TV series Breaking Bad

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Supervisor, Bunsen – Ireland

2021 - Current

This a chain burger company around Ireland

• Working as supervisor demand to have an excellent Customer service, managing and helping floor team during the shift, Controlling the restaurant system, cashier and deliveries, keeping the restaurant a nice place to be.

English Student, International Exchange Program – Ireland

2019 - 2020

Researcher Agent – Statistics and Mapping – Brazilian Institute of Geography and Statistics – **IBGE** Brazil2016-2019

- Responsible for office administration, sales team supervision, technical support, monitoring excellence in customer service
- Supported the IT infrastructure in debugging the Oracle GC system, providing basic server maintenance and repairs, and communicating with supplier Help Desk to troubleshoot technical issues
- Production and analysis of statistical information by technological system
- Coordinated interviews and colleting of many types of information/data with families, public offices and city halls also with market and justice department.

REFERENCES AVAILABLE UPON REQUEST